

# d exstojeba

# **EMAIL**

astojeba@gmail.com

# **WEBSITE**

www.alexstojeba.com

PHONE +4917680514150

# **ABOUT ME**

I am a data-driven, user-focused designer with a background in content and marketing. I excel in applying Design Thinking to all challenges to deliver better results. During my several years of experience working in startups, I have initiated and overseen marketing campaigns and user touch points, optimized content through data analysis, and cultivated SEO and SEA expertise. In addition, I have excellent communication and presentation skills, along with bilingual proficiency in English and German.

**TOOLS** 

### SKILLS

User Research **Prototyping** Sketch Google Analytics **User Testing** Visual Design Invision Sistrix User Interviews Marketing Balsamiq Wordpress **User Personas** SEO Figma TYPO3 **HTML** SEA **Usability Hub** Basecamp **CSS** Infographics Asana Copywriting Wireframing

# **EXPERIENCE**

### **Online Marketing Intern**

Mar 2018-Jul 2018

### Wellnow

- Developed and executed German-language SEO content strategy for the B2B website and editorial page
- Utilized Sistrix, Searchmetrics, Google Analytics, Google AdWords, and other SEO tools for keyword planning and content strategy development
- Reorganized and optimized user onboarding process and drafted initial content for various touchpoints

# **Translator & Content Editor**

Dec 2016-Sep 2017

# Companisto

- Translated and transcreated texts for budding startups including: financial plans, press releases, newsletters, video subtitles and website material
- Delivered tailor-made content to marketing teams and entrepreneurs
- Delegated tasks to a team of external translators

### **Junior Editor**

Jan 2016-Nov 2016

### **Performics**

- Produced and translated editorial and SEO texts for clients like 1&1 and Fitbit, which led to increased traffic and conversion
- Carried out keyword strategy research for on-page web content
- Managed team deadlines, led regular meetings, directed internal team communication

# **EDUCATION**

# Certificate in User Experience Design

CareerFoundry, 2017-2018

Specializations: Front End Development (HTML, CSS & JavaScript), Voice Design

## **Bachelor of Arts**

University of Missouri 2007-2010

Double Major: German and Political Science

Focus: International Relations

# **AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

### Pädagogischer Austauschdienst

Sept 2012 - Jun 2013

FOREIGN LANGUAGE ASSISTANT

# The William J. Fulbright Scholarship

Sept 2011- Jun 2012

FULBRIGHT SCHOLAR